Contact

allard.jim@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/drjimallard (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Patient Advocacy
Patient Education
Quality Improvement

Certifications

Nurse Executive Advanced (NEA-BC)

Registered Nurse

Dr. Jim Allard, DNP, RN, NEA-BC

Vice President & Chief Nursing Officer

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Summary

Experienced nursing leader with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Top 5 themes from CliftonStrengths(TM) include, Arranger, Strategic, Responsibility, Positivity and Achiever. Skilled in Pediatric Acute & Critical Care, Performance Improvement, Medical-Surgical, JCAHO, Transformational Leadership and a passion for a Just Culture and eliminating workplace incivility through education. Strong operations professional with a Doctorate in Nurse Practice from Texas Christian University.

My personal leadership vision is, "Uncovering the leader in every nurse."

Experience

Medical City Children's Hospital and Medical City Woman's Hospital Dallas

Vice President & Chief Nursing Officer Woman's & Children's March 2020 - Present (3 months)

Dallas, Texas

HCA Houston Healthcare Clear Lake Assistant Chief Nursing Officer July 2018 - March 2020 (1 year 9 months) Webster, Texas

Blessed to have the opportunity to serve in the ACNO role at a full service, quaternary acute care hospital. "Above all else, we are committed to the care and improvement of life."

HCA Houston Healthcare, The Woman's Hospital of Texas ACNO & VP Pediatric Services April 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 4 months) Houston, Texas

Extremely excited to serve and learn in this leadership role with an exceptional team of healthcare professionals delivering care to woman, infants and children in Houston and surrounding areas.

Medical City Children's Hospital
Director of Pediatric Services
July 2013 - March 2017 (3 years 9 months)

Children's Medical Center Dallas 8 years 10 months Clinical Manager Cardiac ICU September 2008 - July 2013 (4 years 11 months)

RN Staff Nurse / Team Leader October 2004 - September 2008 (4 years)

Memorial Hermann Healthcare System Pediatric Transport Team 2001 - 2004 (3 years)

Education

HCA Executive Development Program CNO · (2017 - 2018)

Texas Christian University

DNP, Doctor of Nursing Practice - Executive Leadership, Registered Nursing, Nursing Administration, Nursing Research and Clinical Nursing · (2015 - 2017)

The University of Texas at Arlington MSN, Nursing · (2010 - 2013)

Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center BSN, Nursing · (2006 - 2007)

University of New England ADN, Nursing · (1996 - 1998)